enterprisedb.com 2019-06-27

# Privacy Policy | EnterpriseDB

## **Welcome!**

The Privacy Policy posted on this Site was updated on or about October 15, 2018.

EnterpriseDB has created this privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") to demonstrate our commitment to protecting an individual's right to protect his/her personal data. What do we mean by personal data?  

‘Personal data’ means any information relating to a person that can be used to identify such person, directly or indirectly.  For instance, using an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

This Privacy Policy is effective as to websites, events, and other services operated by EnterpriseDB and incorporates by reference our [Terms of Use](https://www.enterprisedb.com/terms-use). Terms with initial capital letters used in this Privacy Policy shall have the respective meanings assigned to them in the Terms of Use, unless specifically defined in this document. The terms "EnterpriseDB," "we," and "our" refer to EnterpriseDB Corporation. The terms "you" and "your" refer to any individual who accesses and uses any of our services, including our websites and online services, including [www.enterprisedb.com](https://www.enterprisedb.com/) (the “Website”); and our live events and conferences (“Events”), and surveys, contests, and sweepstakes (together, the “Services”).

By using this Website, you freely and knowingly consent to the collection and use of information as described herein. EnterpriseDB reserves the right to make changes periodically to this Privacy Policy in our sole discretion. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted on this page. Your continued use of this Website after any such changes constitutes your acceptance of the changes and of the revised Privacy Policy.

## **Scope of this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy applies only to Personal Data collected by EnterpriseDB through software interactions with the EnterpriseDB website (the “Site”) and does not apply to any other information collected by EnterpriseDB through other means unless otherwise specified. If you have other agreements with EnterpriseDB governing EnterpriseDB products and services, then those agreements control with regard to the subject matter of those agreements. Further, our Privacy Policy does not cover the activities of any third parties.

With respect to personal data of residents of the European Economic Area (EEA), EnterpriseDB Corporation (“EnterpriseDB”) complies with the E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and Switzerland to the United States.  EnterpriseDB has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. For more information about our Privacy Shield certifications, please see this [EnterpriseDB E.U.-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Notice](https://www.enterprisedb.com/privacy-shield-policy).

## **This Privacy Policy covers:**

  * **The information we collect**

  * **The basis for processing your information**

  * **How we use your personal information**

  * **How we may share or disclose your personal information**

  * **What cookies and web beacons are and how we and others use them**

  * **What internet protocol addresses are**

  * **Collection of information by third-party sites and sponsors**

  * **How we secure and store your information**

  * **Your rights if you are a California resident**

  * **Our policy towards children**

  * **What choices do we give you, and how can you correct or review your personal information**

  * **How to contact us**

  * **How we may update our privacy policy**

### **The Information We Collect**

EnterpriseDB collects certain personal data when you:

  * Register for any service of EnterpriseDB (e.g., downloading whitepapers, software, etc.);

  * Submit requests, suggestions, or other communications to us;

  * Interact with the Website or EnterpriseDB in any way that submits, releases or displays your personal data to EnterpriseDB (e.g., attending events, entering contests, participating in trainings, etc.).

In interacting or registering with EnterpriseDB or requesting information, you may provide us with a password, your real name, industry, organization name, job role, and contact information, such as e-mail address, phone number, and shipping address. We may also collect your product registration information, product interest information, transaction information, or demographic information. In addition, for certain licensees, EnterpriseDB may require additional information, such as student verification information. We may collect payment information such as your credit card number and billing address if you purchase or license products and services from us. If you connect with EnterpriseDB accounts on third party social networking sites, we may also collect information about your social networking accounts, for example, your name, user name or handle, public profile, and email address. We may also combine information you provide with data we collect automatically (as further described below) and with data we receive from third parties.

Whenever you visit the EnterpriseDB website, EnterpriseDB also receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your computer's or mobile device's operating system type and version, browser type and language, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, and geographic areas derived from your IP address, EnterpriseDB cookie information, file information, time stamped logs regarding access times and duration of visits, the websites you visited before coming to Website, and other usage data relating to your activities on our Sites, including the pages you request. We may relate this information to the personal data you provide for purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Certain third parties, including analytics companies, advertisers and ad networks, may also automatically collect information about you through our Website, using cookies, Web beacons, and device identifiers, including personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, online channels and applications when you use our Website.

### **The Basis for Processing Your Information**

EnterpriseDB processes your personal data based on the following lawful grounds:  

  * **Legitimate Interests:** As necessary for our legitimate interests in carrying out our business, such as sharing information related to your demonstrated interest in database and enterprise information technology, trial software downloads, or other products and services, provided those interests are not outweighed by your rights and interests;
  * **Contract:** As necessary to enter and perform a contract with you, such as when you ask us to provide services to you;
  * **Legal Obligation:** When we have a legal obligation to carry out the processing, such as complying with an applicable law; or
  * **Consent:** Where processing is based on your consent, such as when you have opted in to receive marketing communications from us, we will identify the processing purposes and provide you with relevant information to make the processing fair and transparent. Please click here to learn more about how you may let us know if you no longer wish to receive further marketing emails.

### **How We Use Your Personal Data**

EnterpriseDB may use your personal data to:

  * Provide and deliver products, content, or services you’ve requested, including software updates. If you enter a sweepstake, contest, or similar EDB promotion, we may use your personal data to administer such promotion and/or market relevant products and services based on your demonstrated interest;

  * Operate and improve our internal operations, systems, products, and services;

  * Understand you and your preferences to enhance your experience;

  * Carry out the sales, sales solicitation, shipment of products, complete orders, and provide other services performed by us or third parties;

  * Communicate with you about promotions, upcoming events, and news about products and services offered by EnterpriseDB and our selected partners;

  * Provide system maintenance or handle system malfunctions;

  * Respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;

  * Send you service-related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;

  * Link or combine information about you with other personal data we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better and more personalized service;

  * Enforce our terms and conditions or protect our business, partners, or users;

  * Protect against, investigate, and deter fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity;

  * Carry out identity verification and authentication services; and/or

  * Other separately and explicitly prescribed purposes.

### **How We May Share or Disclose Your Personal Information**

EnterpriseDB does not rent, sell, or share personal data about you with other people or unaffiliated companies, except under the following circumstances:

  * We may provide your personal data to third parties who help facilitate the Website (for example, by providing website development, statistical analyses, data processing, or sending communications to users), but for use solely in connection with facilitating the Website;

  * We may provide your personal data to financial institutions, credit card companies, collection enterprises, and other enterprises that process payments or represent the buyer or seller to facilitate payment owed to us or to a seller when you submit such personal data for the purposes of effecting a purchase or other financial transaction;

  * We may produce certain contests, sweepstakes, and special events with the support of affiliated or non-affiliated sponsors and/or promotional partners. The information collected in conjunction with events may also be used for the marketing of additional services and events by us and/or our promotional partners and sponsors beyond the contest, sweepstakes, and/or special event;

  * We may provide your personal data to persons who owe us a duty of confidentiality in connection with a legitimate business purpose of EnterpriseDB;

  * We may provide your personal data to third parties, including, but not limited to, law enforcement agencies, state, local or federal governments, private litigants, and other companies, as may be required to (1) comply with lawful requests such as subpoenas or court orders, (2) comply with applicable state, federal, or local law, (3) prevent fraud or other illegal activities from being perpetrated through the Website, or (4) protect the property, safety, or legal rights of EnterpriseDB and its users;

  * We may provide your personal data to any third party whom you have consented to receive your personal information;

  * We may provide your personal data to affiliated companies or business successors of EnterpriseDB;

  * We may provide your personal data to third parties as otherwise separately and explicitly prescribed; and/or

  * We may provide your personal data as a result of mergers and acquisitions related to EnterpriseDB.

We will not provide your personal data to third party advertisers, except as provided in this Privacy Policy, without your permission; however, we may provide non-personal data, such as your age, interests, or the way you use the Website, to any third party for any purpose including customizing and targeting advertising messages.

### **What Cookies and Web Beacons Are and How We and Others Use Them**

Our Site may use various software technologies including “cookies,” “web beacons” and “pixel tags.” “Cookies” are small text files that we and others may place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Cookies themselves do not contain any personal data. "Web beacons" or “Pixel tags” are small pieces of code placed on a web page or within the body of an email to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page or viewing or opening an email. For example, web beacons can be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page. We may use web beacons on our Website from time to time for this and advertising purposes.

We use cookies to deliver personalized content, to save you having to re-enter your password repeatedly, to keep track of your shopping cart, and to tailor our information offerings relating to how you and others use the Website. From time to time, we partner with third parties who may place cookies on your browser when you visit our Websites, may send their own cookies to your cookie file, and may use those cookies to track and collect information about you and your online activities over time and across different websites, devices, and applications and to provide targeted advertising based on your interests and previous browsing history. Some cookies remain on your mobile phone, computer or mobile device until they are deleted.

Certain third party ad networks may automatically collect information about your visits to our Sites and other websites, such as your IP address, your Internet service provider, and the browser you use to visit our Sites. They do this using cookies, web beacons or other technologies. You can learn more about practices of many of these third parties by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance (<https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) in the USA, Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (<https://youradchoices.ca/>) in Canada or the European Digital Advertising Alliance (<https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>) in Europe. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or web beacons and other technologies in third party advertising. We encourage you to check the privacy policies of third party advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies, web beacons and other technology.

Some web browsers (including some mobile web browsers) provide settings that allow you to control or reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer, tablet or mobile device. Although you are not required to accept cookies, if you block or reject them, you may not have access to all features available through our services. For more information, visit the help page for your web browser.

### **What Internet Protocol Addresses Are**

An Internet protocol (“IP”) address is the unique number assigned to your server or Internet Service Provider (“ISP”). EnterpriseDB may track such IP addresses for system administration, to report aggregate information, site tracking, to prevent our servers from being abused and for other uses described in this Privacy Policy.

### **Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites and Sponsors**

The following third parties may collect information through the Website, including personal data:

  * Third parties that help facilitate the Website may, from time to time, collect information through the Website in the course of providing support;

  * Third party advertisers may collect information about your mobile phone, computer or mobile device relating to the way you interact with the Website, or which third party advertisers you visit;

  * Third parties may collect other information that you voluntarily post or publish through the Website in any way;

  * Web-crawlers such as Google may collect information through the Website; and/or

  * The Website may contain links or references to other websites, including third party advertisers and other unaffiliated websites.

### **How We Secure and Store Your Personal Data**

We have put in place reasonable and appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in an effort to help safeguard information we collect through our Sites. However, you should know that no company, including EnterpriseDB, can fully eliminate security risks associated with personal data. To help protect yourself, please use a strong password, do not use the same passwords to access your EnterpriseDB accounts that you use with other accounts or services, and protect your user names and passwords to help prevent others from accessing your accounts and services.

EnterpriseDB is a global company with affiliates, varied business processes, management structures and technical systems that cross borders. Information collected by EnterpriseDB or on our behalf may be stored on your computers, on your mobile devices, or on our servers, and may be transferred to, accessed from, or stored and processed in, the United States and other countries including but not limited to the Netherlands, England, France, Australia, Japan, South Korea, Pakistan, India, and any other country where EnterpriseDB or its service providers maintain facilities or support centers (a list of EnterpriseDB offices can be found here: <https://www.enterprisedb.com/locations>), including jurisdictions that may not have data privacy laws that provide protections equivalent to those provided in your home country. However, we will protect all personal data we obtain in accordance with this Privacy Policy and take reasonable steps to ensure that it is treated lawfully. Personal data we collect may be retained for as long as needed to fulfill legitimate business purposes, including the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, or for a period of time specifically required or allowed by applicable regulations or laws.

Personal data we collect may be retained for as long as needed to fulfill legitimate business purposes, including the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, or for a period of time specifically required or allowed by applicable regulations or laws.

### **Your Rights If You Are a California Resident**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of our website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to the EnterpriseDB Legal Department at [legal@enterprisedb.com](mailto:legal@enterprisedb.com) or write us at 34 Crosby Drive, Suite 201, Bedford, MA 01730.

### **Our Policy Towards Children**

EnterpriseDB does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13). If we learn that we have inadvertently obtained Personally Identifiable Information from a child under the age of thirteen (13), we will delete that information as soon as practicable. If you believe that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has submitted Personally Identifiable Information in connection with the Website, please contact us at [legal@enterprisedb.com](mailto:legal@enterprisedb.com).

### **What Choices Do We Give You and How Can You Correct or Review Your Personal Data**

#### **Account Information & Retention**

Upon request, we will provide an individual with access to personal data that we have collected about them (provided that they have given adequate proof of identity). We also offer individuals the ability to have inaccuracies corrected within their contact information. You may also request deletion of your personal data. We will honor requests as required by law and subject to our business and legal needs to retain your data. These information requests can be made by sending us an e-mail at [privacy@enterprisedb.com](mailto:privacy@enterprisedb.com). We will retain your personal data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Notice. If you wish to deactivate your account, please email us at [privacy@enterprisedb.com](mailto:privacy@enterprisedb.com), but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your personal data for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services, to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

#### **Cookies**

When you use our Websites, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies from our servers. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Website. You can also choose to opt-out of use of cookies by many of our third party advertising partners for delivery of personalized ads by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance (<https://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) in the USA, Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (<https://youradchoices.ca/>) in Canada or the European Digital Advertising Alliance (<https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>) in Europe. If you delete your cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choices.

While we and others give you certain choices, as further outlined in this Policy, there are many ways that Web browser signals and similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of nor honor every mechanism.

#### **Marketing Emails**

Our marketing emails tell you how to "opt-out" of receiving further marketing emails. You may also contact us [marketing-notices@enterprisedb.com](mailto:marketing-notices@enterprisedb.com) with a subject line "Unsubscribe" at any time to let us know that you no longer wish to receive further marketing emails. If you receive a phone call from one of our sales representatives, you can ask them to put you on our email unsubscribe list, or you can call us directly at 781-357-3390 and ask to be unsubscribed from our mailing list. If you opt out, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your accounts and our business dealings with you, and, as allowed by applicable law, requests for your participation in surveys.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you believe EnterpriseDB maintains your personal data in one of the services within the scope of our Privacy Shield certification, you may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our Privacy Shield compliance to [privacy@enterprisedb.com](mailto:privacy@enterprisedb.com). EnterpriseDB will respond within 45 days. If we fail to respond within that time, or if our response does not address your concern, you may contact JAMS, which provides an independent third-party dispute resolution body based in the United States, at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>. JAMS has committed to respond to complaints and to provide appropriate recourse at no cost to you. If neither EnterpriseDB nor JAMS resolves your complaint, you may have the possibility to engage in binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Panel.

If you have questions or suggestions, please email EnterpriseDB at [legal@enterprisedb.com](mailto:legal@enterprisedb.com). Written communication should be sent to:

Attn: Legal Department

EnterpriseDB Corporation

34 Crosby Drive, Suite 201

Bedford, MA 01730

USA

### **How We May Update Our Privacy Policy**

From time to time, we may collect and use PII in ways not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy. If our information practices change we will post any adjustments to our policy on this website and change the “Last Updated” date above. Unless additional notice or consent is required by applicable laws, this will serve as your notification of these changes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, bookmark this page and check back periodically.
